Guide to the Sidney T. Cox papers, ca. 1947-1992
Cox, Sidney T. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sidney T. Cox papers, ca. 1947-1992
8427
Cox, Sidney T.
2 cubic feet.
Research materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sidney T. Cox's files relating to his study of Verdi.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Class of 1947. Sidney T. Cox graduated from Phillips Academy and attended Cornell University until 1943, when he entered the Army, serving in the 63rd Infantry Division in France and Germany. After the war, he returned to Cornell, receiving a B.A. in 1947 and an M.A. in 1948, both in music and English. He studied composition at Cornell with Roy Harris, Aaron Copland, and Robert Palmer at Cornell, Colorado College, and Tanglewood. He was a journalist with the Watertown Daily Times from 1949 until 1955. In 1956 he became executive secretary to the New York State Legislature's Joint Committee on Winter Tourism from 1956-1965, and subsequently worked as a research associate for the Assembly's Ways and Means Committee. He was named to the original Temporary State Commission on Tug Hill in 1973, and served as vice chairman and acting chairman until 1979 when he became a director of the Bank of New Hampshire Corp. He was also an underwriting member for Lloyd's of London. He was a member of the American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers, and a director of the Syracuse Symphony, which performed many of his musical works. He was also an expert on Verdi and an advisory board member of the Institute of Verdi Studies. Cornell's music library was named in his honor.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files relating to his study of Verdi.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cox, Sidney T.; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Verdi correspondence - general, 1959-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Paper and correspondence re. the "Berlin Traviata", 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Documents and correspondence re. Verdi bibliography, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Verdi - purchase correspondence, 1969-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Documents and correspondence re. American Institute for Verdi Studies, 1976-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Verdi Newsletter (Verdi Forum), 1978-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Verdi work catalogues, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Auctions (Verdi materials), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Invoices, 1970-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Verdi notes and projects, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Misc. photocopies and documents re. Verdi, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lecture on "Falstaff", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Verdi's Journey to Artistic Maturity" (lecture), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Verdi - transcriptions, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Newspaper clippings/articles, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Cox's comments on Verdi section of Donald Grout's "A Hitory of Western Music", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cox - Music reviews for Cornell Sun, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Musical arrangements by Cox, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Copies of misc. scores (not Verdi), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Block of wood cut from Ezra's oak for Sidney T. Cox, n.d.; MU-2058 (Box 1)
- Verdi - articles (general), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Inventory of articles on Verdi's operas, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Reviews by Andrew Porter, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Verdi entry in New Grove, 6th ed. (A. Porter), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Verdi - copies of autograph letters, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Articles on "Oberto", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Articles on "Un Giorno di Regno", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Articles on "Nabucco", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Articles on "Lombardi" and "Jérusalem", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Articles on "Ernani", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Articles on "I Due Foscari", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Articles on "Giovanna d'Arco", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Articles on "Alzira", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Articles on "Attila", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Articles on "I Masnadieri", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Articles on "Il Corsaro", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Articles on "Luisa Miller", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Articles on "La Battaglia di Legnano", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Articles on "Stiffelio", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Articles on "Rigoletto", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Articles on "Il Trovatore", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Articles on "La Traviata" (I), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Articles on "La Traviata" (II), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Articles on "La Traviata" (III), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Articles on "I Vespri Siciliani", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Articles on "Aroldo", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Articles on "Un Ballo in Maschera", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Articles on "Inno delle Nazioni", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Articles on "Macbeth", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Articles on "La Forza del Destino", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Articles on "Don Carlos" (I), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Articles on "Don Carlos" (II), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Reviews of Ursula Günther's edition of "Don Carlos", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 33)
- "La Genèse de Don Carlos" (Ursula Günther), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Articles on "Aida", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Articles on the Requiem, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Articles on "Simon Boccanegra", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Articles on "Otello", n.d. (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Articles on "Falstaff" (I), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Articles on "Falstaff" (II), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Diploma for Bachelor of Arts degree at Cornell University, 1947 (Folder MSS Box 88)